thy.com 2018-12-26

# Privacy Policy | Legal Notice | Turkish Airlines ®

**The protection of _Your_ personal data is very important to _Us_ and _We_ want You to feel comfortable when visiting the web site or/and mobile apps (hereinafter to be referred to as “ _Online Channels_ ”). _Our_ biggest concern is the protection of _Your_ privacy when processing personal data and _We_ monitor this very closely in any business operations. _We_ take _Our_ responsibilities regarding the protection of personal information very seriously. _We_ respect _Your_ personal privacy. **

This Privacy Policy describes _Our_ practices related to the use, storage, and disclosure of information _We_ collect from or about _You_ when _You_ access and/or use the _online channels_. By using the _Online Channels,_ _You_ accept the Terms of Use and You agree that _We_ can store and access cookies and IP addresses, and use other methods in order to collect usage data related to the _Online Channels_ in order to improve _Your_ online experience. _We_ reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time and without prior notice. _We_ may not post any changes on the _Online Channels_ , so please check regularly for the most recent version of _Our_ Privacy Policy. 

Please note that if _Your_ personally identifiable information changes, or if _You_ no longer wish to use _Our_ service, _We_ will provide a way to correct or update _Your_ personal information provided to _Us_.

_Online Channels_ may contain links to other websites. Please be aware that _We_ are not responsible for the privacy practices of websites not operated by _Us_. _We_ encourage _You_ to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by the _Online Channels._

If _You_ have any further questions or comments, contact _Us_ using the Contact Us page. 

####  What Does This Privacy Policy Cover?  Learn more >>

_We_ ’ve written this Privacy Policy to let _You_ know how _We_ use _Your_ personal information. In it, _We_ explain the types of personal information _We_ collect, how _We_ collect it, how _We_ store it, what _We_ use it for, how _We_ protect it, and who _We_ may share _Your_ personal information with. Any personal information collected during visits to the _Online Channels_ is processed in accordance with the provisions of Turkish law. _Our_ data protection policy also complies with internal data protection guidelines. 

This Privacy Policy applies to all personal information _We_ process about _You_ in connection with _Your_ relationship with _Us_ as a loyalty program member (including where _You_ have a Miles&Smiles and Turkish Corporate Club account) or a potential customer. By “Personal Information” _We_ mean information about _You_ (where _You_ are, or could be, identified, such as _Your_ name and contact details), _Your_ travel arrangements and purchase history, and information about _Your_ access to the _Online Channels_. 

_We_ need _Your_ assistance to ensure that _Your_ personal data is current, complete, and accurate. Please inform _Us_ of changes to _Your_ personal data by contacting _Us_ and submit _Your_ updated particulars to _Us_ in writing.

_We_ may also request personal data updates from _You_ time to time. It is important to ensure that the personal data contained in _Your_ booking information or flight itinerary is current, complete, and accurate.

####  When Do We Collect Personal Information About You?  Learn more >>

_We_ collect personal information about _You_ when _You_ use _Our_ services (whether directly provided by _Us_ or by another company or agent), when _You_ travel with _Us_ , and when _You_ use the _Online Channels_ , including: 

  * When _You_ book or search for a flight or other products or services on the _Online Channels_. 
  * When _You_ use any services on the _Online Channels_ (check-in, flight status, etc.). 
  * When _You_ book or search for a flight or other products or services through _Our_ other sales channels, such as through a travel agent. 
  * If _You_ join the loyalty schemes (i.e. Miles&Smiles, Turkish Corporate Club) or _Our_ other loyalty schemes or customer programs. 
  * When _You_ contact _Our_ call centers or service agents. 
  * When _You_ travel with _Us_ and use airports where _We_ operate. 
  * When the _Online Channels_ crash and _Your_ transaction fails due to some error. 
  * If _You_ use _Our_ lounge facilities. 
  * If _You_ use _Our_ in-flight entertainment and communication services. 
  * If _You_ complete a customer survey or provide _Us_ with feedback. 
  * If _You_ enter a competition or register for a promotion. 
  * If _You_ choose to interact with _Us_ via social media such as Facebook or Twitter. In addition, _We_ may receive personal information about _You_ from third parties, such as: 
  * Companies contracted by _Us_ to provide services to _You_. 
  * Companies involved in _Your_ travel plans, including airlines involved in _Your_ prior or onward journey, relevant airport operators, and customs and immigration authorities, etc. 
  * Companies (e.g. car hire providers and hotels) that participate in _Our_ loyalty schemes and other customer programs.

####  Why Do We Need Your Personal Information?  Learn more >>

When _You_ use services provided on the _Online Channels_ , _You_ will be asked to provide certain information such as _Your_ name, contact details, and/or debit/credit card details. _We_ will store this information and hold it on computers or otherwise. _We_ will use this information in the following ways: 

• To fulfill _Our_ agreement with _You_ , including processing _Your_ flight, sending _You_ _Your_ itinerary, or contacting _You_ if there is a problem with _Your_ reservation. 

• To administer any contest or other promotional offer _You_ may enter and notify winners. 

• To answer any queries which _You_ may send _Us_ by email. 

• To conduct customer satisfaction surveys so that _We_ can provide _You_ more efficient service. 

• To meet _Our_ legal compliance obligations. 

• For crime prevention and detection. 

• To improve _Our_ services. 

• To personalize _Your_ travel experience. 

• For other direct or indirect marketing purposes. _We_ need to know the names of all passengers traveling. If _You_ are booking a flight on behalf of someone else, _You_ must obtain their consent to use their personal information. _We_ proceed on the basis that _You_ have obtained this consent.

####  Who Do We Share Your Personal Information With?  Learn more >>

_Your_ personal information may be shared within the group of companies controlled by _Our_ parent company. 

In order to facilitate _Your_ travel arrangements, _We_ will often need to share _Your_ personal information with third parties including other airlines and airport operators, customs and immigration authorities, travel agents involved in making _Your_ travel arrangements, and _Our_ customer loyalty partners, such as when _You_ transfer between airlines or use a hotel. _We_ also share _Your_ personal information with third parties who deliver services either to _You_ or to _Us_ , such as companies that provide airport assistance or marketing agencies. 

_We_ do not sell personal information to third parties, and _We_ only allow third parties outside the Turkish Airlines group to send _You_ marketing information where _We_ have _Your_ permission to do so. 

Some of the parties may be located outside the European Union and have access to all or some of the personal data collected by _Us_ (name, passport number, trip details, etc.) in order to fulfill the transport contract or comply with specific legal requirements. 

_Your_ booking information or flight itinerary may be disclosed to the appropriate customs and immigration authorities as required by law. For more information on the customs and immigration programs used by the United States authorities, please visit the following web sites: 

• _**[International Privacy Policy of the US Department of Homeland Security (DHS)](http://www.dhs.gov/privacy-policy) **_

• _[**Secure Flight Program**](http://www.dhs.gov/files/programs/gc_1250693582433.shtm)_

####  How Do We Protect Your Personal Information?  Learn more >>

_We_ are committed to ensuring the security and privacy of the personal data that customers provide. _We_ take every necessary measure available for the personal data provided to avoid the risks associated with their processing in order to protect the security of personal data and, specifically, to prevent their corruption, damage, or use by unauthorized third parties. 

_We_ use technical and organizational security measures to protect the data _We_ hold about _You_ against accidental or deliberate manipulation, loss, deletion, or unauthorized access. _Our_ security measures are being improved continuously as new technology develops. 

_We_ are determined to combat the threat of online identity theft. For this reason, _We_ use a fraud detection system for payments made by credit or debit card. The system is designed to protect customers in case of loss or theft of credit or debit cards.

####  How Can You Keep Your Personal Information Safe and Secure?  Learn more >>

• _Keep Your booking reference confidential._  

When _You_ make a booking, _You_ will be given a booking reference such as a PNR (Passenger Name Record) and/or a ticket number. This will appear on the email confirmation or ticket of each person in _Your_ booking. _You_ should keep _Your_ booking reference confidential at all times. 

Giving _Your_ booking reference to others may allow them to access _Your_ booking details through _Our_ system. If _You_ are traveling with others and would not like _Your_ individual booking details to be accessible by them, _You_ may prefer to have each person make separate bookings, to be paid for individually. 

• _Keep Your loyalty scheme details (i.e. Miles &Smiles number/Registered Customer log-in details) confidential. _

To make sure _Your_ access to the _Online Channels_ is secure, _We_ recommend that customers avoid communicating passwords to others. When _You_ finish using the _Online Channels_ and/or social media accounts (especially if these accounts are linked together) _You_ should log out if others are able to access _Your_ computer or device, and especially when using a public device to access the web. This way, other users will not be able to access _Your_ personal data. 

• _Be aware of and protect yourself against Internet fraud and “phishing.”_  

There is an Internet fraud practice known as "phishing" which is the illegal gathering of personal information by deception. Unsolicited emails are sent to individuals from lists illegally gathered by a third party, and recipients are asked to enter or reconfirm bank or password details into a "cloned" or illegal copy web site. 

For _Your_ protection, please be aware of the following guidance: 

• _You_ will only be asked for _Your_ card payment details if _You_ wish to change or claim a refund of _Your_ booking on the _Online Channels_. _We_ require this information specifically in relation to _Your_ booking. _Our_ Customer Relations team might ask for _Your_ bank details if they are going to credit _Your_ account directly, after _You_ have raised a claim with _Us_.

Click here for _Our_ Cookie Policy
